<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Kitchen/Funk]]></title><description><![CDATA[The Blog for our radio show!!!]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 17:56:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Acid Struggle]]></title><description><![CDATA[You might have noticed that we struggled a lot to define Acid House
in our new show. And you are right, it's really hard to keep up with all…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//acid-struggle/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//acid-struggle/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;515&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;/acid-budda.png&quot; style=&quot;object-fit:contain&quot;&gt;&lt;/img&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have noticed that we struggled a lot to define Acid House
in our new show. And you are right, it&apos;s really hard to keep up with all these sub-genres. There are too many of them. Every few years a new wave of artists comes along tagged with a new genre label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skrillex&quot;&gt;Skrillex&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diplo&quot;&gt;Diplo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Guetta&quot;&gt;David Guetta&lt;/a&gt; House? Nowadays, it is called EDM but the basic formula is the same for almost 40 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, there was only one style. It started all in Chicago, some guys in a basement misused some drum-machines and synthesizers developed to accompany studio musicians, replayed some disco hits and boom we got House music.
Soon after, they found an even more peculiar machine called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roland_TB-303&quot;&gt;Roland TB-303&lt;/a&gt; which could be tweaked to make sounds as distorted and sharp that I always imagined some burning pigeons stuck in a toaster making their last noises. The result is Acid House. My personal favorite will be always always Adonis&apos; with &apos;No Way Back&apos; which sounds like a late night drive through an industrial zone with the devil on your mind you just sold your soul to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xvj1q_L_3iw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be accurate, the TB-303 was already played on some other records before but its sound did not gain mainstream momentum.
Already in 1979, the Indian film musician &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2011/may/10/charanjit-singh-acid-house-ten-ragas&quot;&gt;Charanjit Singh&lt;/a&gt; used the machine extensively to fulfill his vision traditional Ragas on a disco beat.  In 1983, the new wave band Orange Juice featured the instrument in their seminal pop hit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QoqoxCr4054&quot;&gt;&apos;Rip it up&apos;&lt;/a&gt; whose cheerful summer vibe is as far from Acid House as it can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BN8M2irJVJA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, according to Wikipedia, the credits to go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discogs.com/artist/1705-Phuture&quot;&gt;Phuture&lt;/a&gt; and DJ Pierre as the inventors of the Acid sound. But as always, when a new music genre is born it&apos;s hard to point down to one specific person or group as originators. It was a collective effort which did not stop with just producing and publishing records. It was a whole new way of dealing with music, arts and life in general resulting in specific fashion style.
Later in the 80ies, things got a bit more complicated because House travelled to Detroit where some young producers, notably the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Belleville_Three&quot;&gt;Belleville Three&lt;/a&gt; shaped the Techno sound under the influence of some early European electronic artists (Kraftwerk).
In New York producers and DJs remembered the colorful Disco past of the city and formed  Garage House. I don&apos;t wanna recall the whole history of House (we can&apos;t be accurate) but DJs like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skiddle.com/news/all/Tony-Humphries-Interview-New-Jersey-Connection/32128/&quot;&gt;Tony Humphries&lt;/a&gt; or labels such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discogs.com/label/608-Nu-Groove-Records&quot;&gt;Nu-Groove&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discogs.com/label/609-Strictly-Rhythm&quot;&gt;Strictly-Rhythm&lt;/a&gt; hosted some of the finest House records in the decade full of soulful vocals and smooth chords but also some solid Acid bombs such as Bobby Konders&apos; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZkwoJvL_-Yc&quot;&gt;Nervous Acid&lt;/a&gt; which added some Dub and Dancehall vibes to the House formula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime American dance music was exported back to Europe influencing a whole generation of young musicians. Especially, in the UK a lot of local bands adopted the synthesizer and drum machines into their setup creating a sound which does not follow any genre conventions. Bands such as Happy Mondays, Stone-Roses or New-Order had one foot in foot in the concert hall and another one in a sweaty club full of ravers high on ecstasy. But it was not until the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second_Summer_of_Love&quot;&gt;Summer Of Love&lt;/a&gt; in 1988 until Acid House parties were called Raves. Every weekend thousand of ravers went into clubs or outdoor festivals celebrating hedonism as a response to their fad life perspectives in a country which was struck by the neo-liberal bullshit policies we all love so much. For less political mumbo jumbo check out our podcast below. In spirit of acid it&apos;s all DIY funny mistakes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/594667014&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Disco for Old People]]></title><description><![CDATA[Well, I'm Jan 30 years old, born in '88 and my colleague Stephan is 29 born one year later. We like music, sometimes too much. We listen to…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//disco-for-old-ppl/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-starter-blog-demo.netlify.com//disco-for-old-ppl/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Well, I&apos;m Jan 30 years old, born in &apos;88 and my colleague Stephan is 29 born one year later. We like music, sometimes too much. We listen to it while fighting with our Phd topics. Our days are spent  by digging through the vast world of music on the internet trying to find the one hidden gem. On other days we even eat from it quite literally and prepare a radio show (you witness it right now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first post to commemorate our radio show which happens monthly on Xlair radio. Don&apos;t expect anything
professional. We are bloody amateurs without a real agenda except for our conviction that our fascination for
music is worth spreading (it comes straight from the heart)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first topic from our analogue music cuisine is Disco which is really something special for me because it helped through a lot of difficult moments in my youth when growing up in some rural area in Germany. In the beginning, Disco was not more than a word floating around in the media like an old car nobody wants to drive anymore.  It had the same smell as the seats which were old, dusty, moist and too soft. Its echos I found in some antiquated television shows which used it often as a backing track for some poorly executed action scenes. In record stores Disco music was always put in crates on the floor which were hard to reach and sold for nothing more than a few euros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://giphy.com/embed/1PkxzVZ626NdC&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;370&quot; frameBorder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abba was Disco as much as the Bee Gees or John Travolta.
Your parents were Disco. Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll definitely wasn&apos;t.
In short Disco sucked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now this genre  is celebrating a comeback. Paradoxically enough I feel a bit old to explain you why. When going into clubs, I often feel touched to hear all these tracks I listened alone in my room getting finally aired in public. I can&apos;t even fully enjoy it because it seems so surreal! Young people around me crying to Donna Summer or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.popmatters.com/167895-queen-of-disco-the-legend-of-sylvester-2495781452.html&quot;&gt;Sylvester&lt;/a&gt;
I really ask myself how do they got into that? The idea of the dancefloor as a space to be free was the big dream for a generation of young dancers. It did not matter if you are rich or poor, black or white, gay or straight. In the repetition the beat people experienced freedom perhaps for the first time in their life. But in retrospect the Disco movement has failed just as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=NTAH&quot;&gt;Hippies&lt;/a&gt; or Punks did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its early idealism was soon to be caught by reality. Big Money, drug addiction sex work and AIDS found their way to the dancefloor. Young people today don&apos;t realize this, they were never part of the scene. The only thing which is remembered are the songs, these long extended percussive workouts full of funk, soul and the cry for freedom. On Youtube, some Disco tracks have more than 1 million plays which is impressive because they are tools for DJs not meant to be played on a smartphone with these little ear plugs. Some people say that Disco is dead because it is decontextualized and reappropriated from its origin which was marginal, black and gay, thereby losing its soul and serving the big money machine of capitalism. Others say that Disco is still alive after all these years and creating a narrative for new artists, club goers and listeners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As life is, the matter is complicated. But when I&apos;m feeling down and alone Disco kicks my ass and frees my mind. It makes me move forward and shows me what&apos;s possible in life. I hope for you, too. If not just listen to our show below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/574693548&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>